Peiran Wang (王沛 然)

Grade: Third(3rd) Year of Bachelor Degree | Gender: Male | Location: Chengdu, Sichuan Province, China

Email:whilebug@qq.com | Phone:+86-17883693551 | Personal Web:www.whilebug.com

Education Experiences					
09/2018-Present	Sichuan University(985/211) http://scu.edu.cn/, Chengdu, China				
	School of Cyber Science and Engineering (CSE) Cyberspace security Major				
	Cyberspace security Excellent Talent Class (Special selected class)				
	GPA:3.90/4.00 Compulsory Score:91 (Rank 2/172 in my major in the first 5 semesters)				
Awards and Honors					
2018-2019	Annual National Scholarship (for top 2% students)				
2018-2019	Annual Sichuan University First Class Scholarship				
2019-2020	Annual Sichuan University Third Class Scholarship				
2020-2020	Third prize Annual National Mathematical Modeling Competition in Sichuan				
2019-2019	Third prize Annual National Mathematics Competition in Sichuan				
2019-2020	Elite Top 100 Competition Elite Top 100 Award				
2020-2021	National-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program Participants				
2020-2021	Provincial -Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program Participan				
2021-2021	Internet + competition school-level second prize				
2021-2021	Internet + competition school-level golden prize				
Research Experiences					
11/2020 - 04/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University				
	A Framework for Solving non-IID Problems in Federated Learning				
	♦ Proposed A solution to the problem of non-IID data in Federated Learning;				
	♦ Paper accepted by <u>IEEE GlobeCom2021(CCF-C)</u> ;				
11/2020 - 06/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University				
	Byzantine Clients Detection in Federated Learning (Extensive version on proceeding version)				
	Proposed a method to detect and prevent Byzantine nodes in Federated Learning;				
	Paper accepted by <u>ISCC 2021 (CCF-C) Second author(Supervisor first author)</u> ;				
	♦ Extensive paper is submit to <u>ACM TIFS(CCF-A) First student author</u> ;				
04/2020 - 02/2021	Prof. Cheng Huang's Group (https://chenghuang.org/), Sichuan University				
	Javascript Cryptojacking Detection in Web Browser				
	Proposed a static detection method to detect malicious mining JavaScript code in browser;				
	Paper submitted to <u>IEEE TrustCom2021(CCF-C) First author, transferred to IEEE CSE</u> ;				
Program Experiences					
03/2021 - 06/2021	Prof. Beibei Li's Group (https://li-beibei.github.io/), Sichuan University				
	IoT Privacy-Enhancing Platform				
	♦ Developed a privacy protection platform to deal with the leakage of user privacy and IO				
	environment privacy;				

As the team leader, he led the research and development of the project team, which improved

Prepared to participate in the 2021 information security competition national competition /

his project management organization ability and presentation ability;

China University student computer design competition / "Internet+" Competition;

11/2019 - 2020/11 Prof. Cheng Huang's Group (https://chenghuang.org/), Sichuan University

Domestic system terminal situation awareness platform based on machine learning

- ♦ Developed an operating system attack detection system based on machine learning;
- As the team leader, he led the research and development of the project team, which improved the project management organization ability and presentation ability;
- → Top 100 elites Award in 100 Elites Competition 2020;

11/2020 - 06/2021 Prof. Xinjian Xu's Group, School of literature and journalism, Sichuan University

Reconstruction of cultural memory - An Anthropological Study of Li Jieren's "Dahe Trilogy"

- ♦ Analyze project usage statistics in the project;
- ♦ Rated as National-Level College Students' Innovative Entrepreneurial Training Plan Program of Sichuan University in 2021;

Publication

- 1. MineDetector: JavaScript Browser-side Cryptomining Detection using Static Methods (First author, accepted by IEEE CSE 2021)
- 2. FedVANET: Efficient Federated Learning with Non-IID Data for Vehicular Ad Hoc Networks (Accepted by <u>IEEE GlobeCom</u> 2021 CCF-C)
- 3. FLPhish: Reputation-Based Phishing Byzantine Defense in Ensemble Federated Learning (Second author, supervisor is first author (Accepted by IEEE ISCC CCF-C)
- 4. Defending Against Byzantine Attacks in Ensemble Federated Learning: A Bayesian Reputation-based Phishing Approach (Submitted to IEEE TIFS CCF-A)

Research Interest

- AI security:Federated Learning Security/Non-IID in Federated Learning/Inference Attack in AI/Poison Attack in AI
- Data-driven security:Malicious Code Analysis/Cyber Crime/Underground Economy/Social Computing
- System:System Security/Machine Learning System

Language Skills			
01/2019	CET-4	Listening:228 Reading:180 Writing&Translation:191	Total:599
09/2019	CET-6	Listening:208 Reading:202 Writing&Translation:130	Total:540
01/2021	IELTS	Reading: 8.5 Listening: 8.5 Saying: 5.5 Writing: 6.5	Total : 7.5
Grasped Skills			

Research Skills: Deep Learning/Program Management(git)/Database Deployment(mysql)/Data Mining/Data Analysis

Preferred Programming Languages: C/Python/JavaScript/HTML/Matlab/Assembly Language

Professional Skills: SQL Injection/CSRF Attack/XSS Attack/Traffic Analysis/Reverse Engineering/Pwn/Malicious Code Analysis

Biography

After entering Sichuan University, he was selected as the member of Cyberspace Security excellence class of Sichuan University. In the first academic year, he won the national scholarship and the annual first-class scholarship of Sichuan University. In the usual course, he actively answered the teacher's questions, participated in classroom interaction. In the first five semesters, his compulsory grade ranked 2/172, with an average score of 90.72 and GPA of 3.89. He performs well in English, with IELTS score of 7.5, and can communicate with native speakers fluently. He also has rich project experiences, including a national-level undergraduate innovation and entrepreneurship project in 2020-2021 and a provincial-level undergraduate innovation and entrepreneurship project. He has many research experiences and began to participate in scientific research in his sophomore year. One EI conference paper has been received and three papers are being submitted. He is full of enthusiasm for network security research.